tableau.com 2019-12-25

# Tableau Software Privacy Policy | Tableau Software

**Last updated on March 13, 2019.**

Tableau believes in the importance of thoughtfully handling personal information and is committed to privacy practices that are transparent and compliant. This Privacy Policy sets out how Tableau uses the personal information we collect and receive about you.

## Types of Personal Information

Tableau collects personal information in support of its mission to help people see and understand their data. This personal information is collected through a variety of ways. For example, we collect personal information through the registration and use of our software and mobile apps, whether downloaded or accessed through a cloud-based service. We also collect personal information when you use or visit Tableau websites, attend a Tableau hosted or sponsored event, or participate in a Tableau community. We may receive your personal information if you are a Tableau supplier or partner. We may also receive your information from third party partners. If you have other agreements with Tableau, then those agreements control with regard to the subject matter they cover. 

The type of information we collect will depend on your interactions with Tableau. It may include:

**Contact and Log In Information.** Name, employer, title, email address, physical address, phone number, and similar contact info, user names and passwords.

**Payment Information.** Credit card number, banking information and billing address.

**Demographic Information.** Employment status, occupation, region. On occasion, Tableau may collect other demographic information, such as gender, race and age. 

**Registration Information.** Product registration information, product interest information, transaction information, and in some cases, student verification information. We may also collect registration information related to your attendance at Tableau events, including travel info, scheduling information, food preferences or allergies, accessibility requests and others.

**Usage and Geographic Data.** Tableau collects personal information related to your use of our products, services and websites. We analyze that usage data so that we can improve our products and your experience with them. In certain instances, Tableau allows you to use administrative tools to opt out of the collection of some usage data. 

Usage data may include information about your computer's or mobile device's operating system and browser type; your device type; details about how you are using our products (including natural language queries); view your Internet Protocol (IP) address, and geographic areas derived from your IP address; networking connection data; Tableau cookie information; file information; metadata; time stamped logs regarding access times and duration of visits; the websites you visited before coming to Tableau websites; and other usage data relating to your activities on our Sites, including the pages you request. We may link this information to the personal information we have collected about you and use it for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy, and we may deliver targeted marketing and product information back to you based on your usage data. 

**Third Party Data.** We may receive your personal information from third party suppliers or partners. If you connect with Tableau accounts on third party social networking sites, we may receive information about your social networking accounts, for example, your name, user name or display name, public profile, and email address. We may combine information you provide with data we collect automatically and with data we receive from third parties. Certain third parties, including analytics companies, advertisers and ad networks, may automatically collect information about you through our websites using cookies, Web beacons, and device identifiers, including personal information about your online activities over time and across different websites, devices, online channels and applications.

**Images, Video and Recordings.** Pictures, videos or audio recordings may be collected by Tableau. For example, if you attend a Tableau event, your image may be captured in a photo or video. If you call Tableau customer support, your call may be recorded.

If you decline to provide your personal information or ask us to delete it, we may be unable to continue to provide or support our products or services.

### Ways we Use Personal Information

We use the personal information we collect for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy, as covered in any agreement that incorporates this Policy, or as disclosed to you in connection with our websites. For example, we will use your information to:

• Provide and deliver products or services, including software updates;  
• Operate and improve our operations, systems, products, and services;  
• Understand you and your preferences to enhance your experience;  
• Respond to your comments and questions and provide customer service;  
• Provide service and support, such as sending confirmations, invoices, technical notices, updates, security alerts, and administrative messages and providing customer support and troubleshooting;  
• Communicate with you and your referrals about promotions, upcoming events, and news about products and services offered by Tableau and our selected partners;  
• Link or combine information about you with other personal information we get from third parties, to help understand your needs and provide you with better and more personalized service;  
• Enforce our terms and conditions or protect our business, partners, or users; or  
• Protect against, investigate, and deter fraudulent, unauthorized, or illegal activity

### Reasons for Using Your Information

When we process your personal information we will only do so where at least one of the following applies: 

• We need to use your personal information to perform our responsibilities under our contract with you and to provide you with tools and services;  
• We have a legitimate reason to collect and use your personal information. For example, it is in our legitimate interests to use usage data including your personal information to improve our products and services; to tell you about changes to this Privacy Policy and other policies; to tell you about new products, services and events or changes to our products, services or websites; for business reasons (for example to develop and expand our business); and to tell you about offers or promotions we are running;  
• You have given consent to use your personal information. You may withdraw consent by "opting out" where we give you the opportunity to do so, or by contacting us using the contact details below.  
• If it is necessary for us to use your personal information in order to comply with a legal obligation; or  
• You have chosen to make the information public. You should not share any personal information which you wish to keep confidential or private. 

### Sharing of Personal Information 

Tableau works to keep your personal information confidential and secure, and does not sell your personal data. In some circumstances Tableau may share your information with third parties, for example:

• We may share your personal information when we have your permission, including when you choose to share information using Tableau Public or post to our community websites;

• We provide personal information to trusted partners who work on behalf of or with Tableau to provide us with services. For example, we share information with our training and certification partners, our data storage, customer support and marketing vendors and software providers. These companies may use your personal information to perform services and to help Tableau communicate with you about offers from Tableau and our marketing partners. Tableau maintains contracts with these companies restricting their access, use and disclosure of personal information in compliance with this Privacy Policy and any legal obligations;

• If you connect to your third party accounts through our products, we will use that information to authenticate you, enumerate the data sources available to you, download any data you request us to, and download and refresh authentication tokens or persist authentication information such as user names and passwords as necessary to continue to connect to these data;

• We may share your personal information with our current or future affiliates, which may include parent and subsidiary companies, joint ventures, or other companies under common control, in which case we will require our affiliates to honor this Privacy Policy;

• We will disclose your personal information to comply with legal requirements, for example, in response to a court order or a subpoena. We also may disclose your personal information in response to a law enforcement agency's request, or where we believe it is necessary to investigate, verify, prevent, enforce compliance with, or take action regarding illegal or suspected illegal activities; suspected fraud; situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person; protection of the rights and property of Tableau, our agents, customers, or others; violations or suspected violations of our agreements and policies; or as otherwise required or permitted by law or consistent with legal requirements; 

• We transfer or disclose your personal information for corporate reasons. For example, to third parties in connection with or during negotiation of any merger, financing, acquisition, bankruptcy or similar transaction. We may also share personal information with our auditors, attorneys or other advisors in the connection with corporate functions; and

• Finally, we also share aggregated, anonymized or statistical information about you, including demographics data, with others for a variety of purposes, for example, for improving products and services for Tableau and others.

We may facilitate third party services or ways to share data through third parties, including social media platforms, websites, applications, and services through “plug-ins,” widgets, buttons, and other third party features on and connected with our websites, communications or products. Third parties whose services you use in connection with Tableau, such as our training and certification partners, or third parties whose websites we link to, may have information practices that are different from ours. This Privacy Policy does not apply to the activities of third parties when they are collecting or using data for their own purpose or on behalf of others. We are not responsible for the activities of these third parties. We encourage you to review their privacy policies to understand how they use your information.

### Storage and Security of Your Personal Information

We have reasonable and appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures in place to help safeguard your personal information. However, you should know that no company, including Tableau, can fully eliminate security risks associated with personal information. To help protect yourself, use a strong password, do not use the same passwords to access your Tableau accounts that you use with other accounts or services, and protect your user names and passwords to help prevent others from accessing your accounts and services. For more information about Tableau security practices, see [www.tableau.com/security](https://www.tableau.com/security). 

We offer you the ability to post information and exchange ideas through our websites and other services such as Tableau Public. Because your posts and information shared through Tableau Public are public and can be seen by others, we caution all users to consider what they post and not to disclose any personal information. Tableau will not be responsible in the event that you disclose personal information in your posts, through our public services or during any other communication with other website users.

Information collected by Tableau or on our behalf may be stored on your computers, on your mobile devices, or on our servers, and may be transferred to, accessed from, or stored and processed in, the United States and other countries including but not limited to Ireland, the United Kingdom, France, Germany, Sweden, the Netherlands, Australia, Singapore, Japan, India, and China, and any other country where Tableau or its service providers maintain facilities or support centers (a list of Tableau offices can be found here: [www.tableau.com/about/contact](https://www.tableau.com/about/contact)), including jurisdictions that may not have data privacy laws that provide protections equivalent to those provided in your home country. However, we will protect all personal information we obtain in accordance with this Privacy Policy and take reasonable steps to ensure that it is treated lawfully. 

In certain circumstances we may retain your personal information after you have closed your account or are no longer actively engaged with Tableau. For example:

• We may retain your personal information after you have closed your account so that we can send you information about products, services and publications we think you may be interested in. You can "unsubscribe" to receiving such messages or tell us you are no longer interested;

• We may retain your personal information in order to protect our legal rights, or those of third parties, or to comply with the law; and

• We may retain personal information about how you have used our products and services in order to improve and develop our business.

• If you purchase products or services from us, we may retain your personal information for as long as we need to in order to provide you with customer service, or for compliance purposes, for example, in order to comply with our record keeping requirements.

• Tableau may also use and share aggregated, non-personally identifiable data for research, external training and marketing purposes. 

## Controlling your Personal Information

Our marketing emails permit you to "opt-out" of receiving further marketing emails. You may contact us at [customerservice@tableau.com](mailto:customerservice@tableau.com) at any time to let us know that you no longer wish to receive further marketing emails. If you opt-out, we may still send you transactional emails. Transactional emails include emails about your accounts and our business dealings with you, such as renewals and updates, and, as allowed by applicable law, requests for your participation in surveys. 

When you use our websites, you can usually choose to set your browser to remove cookies and to reject cookies from our servers. If you choose to remove or reject cookies, this could affect certain features or services of our websites. For information about how to remove or manage cookies please read our cookie policy. 

You may have the right, depending on which country you reside in, to ask us to provide a copy of the personal information we hold about you (provided that we may ask you for proof of your identity). You may also have the right to ask us to correct any inaccuracies in your personal information or to ask us to delete it. We will consider these requests regardless of where you live.

In addition, if you are based in Europe and accessing our Sites, then you also have the right to ask us to:

• Confirm whether or not personal information about you is being processed;  
• Provide you with details about how we process your personal information;  
• Consider your valid objection to the processing of your personal information (including the right to object to processing on grounds relating to your particular situation where we are relying on our legitimate interests as a legal basis for processing your personal information);  
• Update or delete personal information which we hold about you;  
• Restrict the way we process your personal information;  
• Consider your valid request to transfer your personal information to a third party provider of services (data portability); and  
• Ask us to treat your consent as withdrawn if you have previously provided us with consent to process your personal information and we rely on it as our legal basis for processing.

If you need help or wish to exercise any of the above rights or have questions about them, please contact us at [privacy@tableau.com](mailto:privacy@tableau.com). We will consider all such requests and provide our response as soon as we can. Please note, however, that personal information may be exempt from such requests in certain circumstances, which may include circumstances where we need to keep processing your personal information for our legitimate interests or to comply with a legal obligation. We may request you provide us with information necessary to confirm your identity. 

### Cookies and Web Beacons 

Our websites may use various software technologies including “cookies,” “web beacons” and “pixel tags.” “Cookies” are small text files that we and others may place in visitors' computer browsers to store their preferences. We use "Web beacons" or “Pixel tags” - small pieces of code placed on a web page or within the body of an email - to monitor the behavior and collect data about the visitors viewing a web page or viewing or opening an email. Web beacons can be used to count the users who visit a web page or to deliver a cookie to the browser of a visitor viewing that page, and we use them from time to time for this and advertising purposes.

We partner with third parties who may place cookies on your browser when you visit our websites, may send their own cookies to your cookie file, and may use those cookies to track and collect information about you and your online activities over time and across different websites, devices, and applications and to provide targeted advertising based on your interests and previous browsing history.

Third party ad networks may automatically collect information about your visits to our websites and other websites, such as your IP address, your Internet service provider, and the browser you use to visit our websites. They do this using cookies, web beacons or other technologies. You can learn more about practices of many of these third parties by visiting the Digital Advertising Alliance ([www.aboutads.info/choices](http://www.aboutads.info/choices)) in the USA, Digital Advertising Alliance of Canada ([https://youradchoices.ca](https://youradchoices.ca/)) in Canada or the European Digital Advertising Alliance ([www.youronlinechoices.eu](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/)) in Europe. This Privacy Policy does not apply to, and we are not responsible for, cookies or web beacons and other technologies in third party advertising. We encourage you to check the privacy policies of third party advertisers and/or ad services to learn about their use of cookies, web beacons and other technology. For more information about the cookies and related technologies used on our websites, please refer to our Cookie Policy ([www.tableau.com/cookies](https://www.tableau.com/cookies)).

### Privacy Shield and Data Transfer

For the personal information of residents of the European Union and the United Kingdom, Tableau adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles (as outlined here: [www.privacyshield.gov/welcome](http://www.privacyshield.gov/welcome)) and is an active participant in the EU-US Privacy Shield framework. Tableau also complies with the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framwork as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from Switzerland to the United States. Our Privacy Shield certification covers the types of personal information set out in this Privacy Policy, and Tableau is subject to the investigative and enforcement powers of the Federal Trade Commission. 

Tableau complies with the Privacy Shield principles for onward transfers, including the liability provisions. If we transfer your personal information to third parties outside the UK, the EU or Switzerland, we will only do so where one of the following applies:

• In the case of transfers of personal information to the US, if the recipient is a member of the Privacy Shield Framework;  
• Where we have in place standard model contractual clauses approved by the European Commission or other legally compliant terms; or  
• There is an adequacy decision by the European Commission which means that the recipient country is deemed to provide adequate protection for such personal information.

You may direct any inquiries or complaints concerning our Privacy Shield compliance to [privacy@tableau.com](mailto:privacy@tableau.com). You may also contact JAMS, at [www.jamsadr.com/eu-us-privacy-shield](http://www.jamsadr.com/eu-us-privacy-shield). JAMS is a Privacy Shield dispute resolution mechanism. JAMS has committed to respond to complaints and to provide appropriate recourse at no cost to you. If neither Tableau nor JAMS resolves your complaint, you may have the possibility to engage in binding arbitration through the Privacy Shield Panel. You may also make a complaint to the relevant EU data privacy supervisory authority or the Swiss Federal Data Protection and Information Commissioner. 

### How to contact us

Tableau Software, Inc. is a member of a group of companies located in North America, the European Economic Area, Asia, and Australia. Click on this link for a complete, up-to-date list of our group companies who may process your personal information: [www.tableau.com/about/contact](https://www.tableau.com/about/contact).

If you have any questions about how we use your personal information, or if you have any other privacy-related questions, please contact us at [privacy@tableau.com](mailto:privacy@tableau.com) or at Tableau Software, Inc., Attn: Tableau Legal, 1621 N 34th St., Seattle, Washington 98103 or The Oval, Shelbourne Road, Dublin 4, Ireland.

#### Updates

From time to time, we will update this Privacy Policy. In the event there are material changes to our information practices, we will note those changes on Tableau’s Privacy Policy webpage ([www.tableau.com/privacy](https://www.tableau.com/privacy)) and in some cases send a notification of changes via email.
